CURRICULUM VITAE

Joo Young Kim Mar 16, 2022

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Work Address: 222 Wangsimni-ro Seongdong-gu, Seoul 04763 **Home Address**: 459-18 Deongneung-ro Nowon-gu, Seoul 01769

Citizenship: Republic of Korea

Email: jykim1026@hanyang.ac.kr

Personal Website: https://jooyoungkim.info Laboratory Website: https://suh.hanyang.ac.kr

PhD candidate and Technical Research Personnel in the Biomedical Engineering Department at Hanyang University, South Korea.

I work with Professor In Young Kim in the Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.

I completed my B.S. in Biomedical Engineering at Hanyang University and can handle most bio-signals and medical images. In particular, I can design the whole systems for electrical bio-signals, including hardware design, firmware coding and analysis.

Through the analysis of bio-signals and medical images, I have become interested in computer science and have a need for related research. So, we created an A.I. team in the lab and I am currently working on this team, doing CNN and RNN based research.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL APPOINTMENTS

EDUCATION:

2016-Present Ph.D. candidate, Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

Supervisor: In Young Kim (M.D., Ph.D.)

2012-2016 B.Sc. Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

HONORS, AWARDS:

2017 Best Paper Award The Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering
2015 Dean's Award Graduation Project, Department of Biomedical Engineering,

Hanyang University

2015 The Encouragement Award 7th Capstone Design Fair Final, Hanyang University

RESEARCH

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE:

2016-Present Graduate Research Assistant, A.I. team, Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.,

Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

2015-2016 Undergraduate Research Intern, Hearing team, Smart Ubiquitous Healthcare Lab.,

Biomedical Engineering, Hanyang University, Seoul, Korea

2017-Present Research Assistant, Smart Healthcare & Device Research Center,

Samsung Medical Center, Seoul, Korea

MAJOR AREAS OF RESEARCH INTEREST

Machine learning and deep learning in medical data

Biomedical engineering, Computer science, Electrical engineering

PUBLICATIONS:

REFEREED JOURNAL ARTICLES (SCI | SCI-E): * lead author; ^ co-author

- Nam, B.*, <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Kim, I. Y., Cho, B.H., (2022).
 Selective Prediction LSTM for Time Series Health Datasets using Unit-wise Batch Standardization: Algorithm Development and Validation.
 JMIR Medical Informatics, 10(3):e30587
- Ro, K.*, <u>Kim, J. Y.*</u>, Park, H., Cho, B.H., Kim, I. Y., Shim, S.B., Choi, I.Y., Yoo, J.C. (2021). Deep-learning framework and computer assisted fatty infiltration analysis for the supraspinatus muscle in MRI. *Scientific Reports*, 11(1), 1-12.
- 3. You, S.*, Cho, B. H., Yook, S. <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Shon, Y. -M, Seo, D. -W., Kim, I. Y. (2020). Unsupervised automatic seizure detection for focal-onset seizures recorded with behind-the-ear EEG using an anomaly-detecting generative adversarial network. *Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine*, 193, 105472
- Kim, J. Y.*, Ro, K.*, You, S., Nam, B. R., Yook, S., Park, H. S., ... & Kim, I. Y. (2019). Development of an automatic muscle atrophy measuring algorithm to calculate the ratio of supraspinatus in supraspinous fossa using deep learning.
 Computer Methods and Programs in Biomedicine, 182, 105063.
- 5. <u>Kim, J. Y.*</u>, Nam, K. W., Lee, J. C., Hwang, J. H., Jang, D. P., & Kim, I. Y. (2018). Scalp tapping-based protocol for adjusting the parameters of binaural hearing aids. *Biomedical Signal Processing and Control*, 45, 91-97.
- 6. Kim, D. Y.*, Kwon, J., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Cha, H. S., Kim, Y. W., Kim, I. Y., & Im, C. H. (2018). New Method for Pure-Tone Audiometry Using Electrooculogram: A Proof-of-Concept Study. *Sensors*, 18(11), 3651.

REFEREED JOURNAL ARTICLES (DOMESTIC): * lead author; ^ co-author

- Kim, J. Y.*, Nam, B.R., Kim, M.S., Choi, J.K., Cho, B.H. & Kim, I. Y. (2021).
 Technical Note: Speaker Identification Algorithm Based on the Deep Learning for Phonetics
 Forensic Purposes using a Cochlear Simulation Spectrum.
 Journal of Science Criminal Investigation, 15(4): 307-311
- Nam, B.R., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, Kim, M.S., Choi, J.K., Cho, B.H. & Kim, I. Y. (2021). Technical Note: Development of Non-contact Deception Detection using Facial Expression and Analysis of Significant Time Period. *Journal of Science Criminal Investigation*, 15(3), 238-243.
- 3. So, S., You, S. M., <u>Kim, J. Y.^</u>, An, H. J., Cho, B. H., Yook, S., & Kim, I. Y. (2018). Development of Age Classification Deep Learning Algorithm Using Korean Speech. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering Research*, 39(2), 63-68.

4. <u>Kim, J.*</u>, Lee, S., Kim, K., Cho, K., You, S., So, S., ... & Kim, I. Y. (2017). Development of Bone Metastasis Detection Algorithm on Abdominal Computed Tomography Image using Pixel Wise Fully Convolutional Network. *Journal of Biomedical Engineering Research*, 38(6), 321-329.

PATENTS:

1. NAM, Bo Rum, KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, **KIM, Joo Young**, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Yeong Myeong, KIM, Ji Yoon

"Involuntary Emotional Expression Extraction and Quantification Using Facial Landmarks" KR-Application No. 10-2019-0147279

Patent No. 10-2338684

 KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, <u>KIM, Joo Young</u>, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Yeong Myeong, NAM, Bo Rum, KIM, Ji Yoon "DECEPTION DETECTION METHOD USING BIOMETRIC INFORMATION" KR-Application No. 10-2020-0153434

3. KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Joo Young, KIM, Yeong Myeong, KIM, Ji Yoon, NAM, Bo Rum
"DECEPTION DETECTION METHOD AND APPARATUS USING THERMAL VIDEO"
KR-Application No. 10-2019-0140579

 KIM, In Young, YOOK, Soon Hyun, <u>KIM, Joo Young</u>, YOU, Sung Min, KIM, Yeong Myeong, NAM, Bo Rum, KIM, Ji Yoon
 "DECEPTION DETECTION METHOD USING BIOMETRIC INFORMATION" KR-Application No. 10-2019-0091422

PROJECTS:

 Objective measurement and assessment of rehabilitation for the stroke patient based on the Inertial Measurement Unit and Electromyography Signal Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea (Apr. 2015 ~ Aug. 2015)

 Development of Deep Brain Stimulation Therapeutic Technique for Depression based on micro PET and Fast Scan Cyclic Voltammetry Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea (Mar. 2015 ~ Oct. 2015)

■ Development of a system to predict cardiac arrest using complex biosignals Korea Health Industry Development Institute, KHIDI, Korea (Oct. 2015 ~ Apr. 2016, Mar. 2018 ~ Dec. 2018)

■ Development of band-typed wearable monitoring device and extraction of biological markers Ministry of Science and ICT, Korea (Apr. 2016 ~ Sep. 2016, Apr. 2017 ~ Sep. 2017)

 Development of personal authentication system based on multi-modal biometrics Ministry of Education, Korea (Aug. 2016 ~ Oct. 2016)

 Development of videofluoroscopic swallowing image-based automatic diagnosis and classification techniques for dysphagia patients
 Ministry of Education, Korea (Nov. 2016 ~ Oct. 2017) Low-intensity Focused Ultrasound Based Tactile & Texture Generating Technology Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd., Korea (Jul. 2017 ~ Mar. 2018)

■ 전투원 생존성 지표 도출을 위한 다생체신호 계측 및 복합 분석

(Multi-biological signal measurement and complex analysis for deriving combatant survivability indicators)

Agency for Defense Development, ADD, Korea (Oct. 2016 ~ Dec. 2016, Nov. 2017 ~ Dec. 2017)

- Development of Multimodal Brain-Machine Interface SystemBased on User Intent Recognition Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, Korea (Mar. 2017 ~ Feb. 2018)
- 뇌파 기반 상태 판단 로직 개발 (Development of EEG-based state classification logic) HYUNDAI MOBIS CO. LTD., Korea (Aug. 2017 ~ Oct. 2017)
- Construction of multi-modal biometrics and Korean voice database for development of forensic science technique
 Ministry of Science and ICT, Korea (Jun. 2017 ~ Jun. 2022)
- Structuring of Korean medicine classic database for development of korean-western medical diagnostic artificial intelligence assistant Korea Health Industry Development Institute, Korea (Mar. 2018 ~ Dec. 2018)
- Development of biosensing fuction antibiosis wounddressing and instrument for the treatment Korea Evaluation Institute of Industrial Technology, Korea (Mar. 2019 ~ Dec. 2020)
- 멀미 정량화 분석 산학연구(Motion sickness quantification analysis industry-university project) HYUNDAI NGV, Korea (Jul. 2019 ~ Nov. 2019)
- VR 어플리케이션을 위한 안면부 근전도 기반 표정 인식 (Facial EMG-based Facial Expression Recognition for Interactive VR Applications) Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd., Korea (Sep. 2019 ~ Aug. 2020)
- 운전자 스트레스 상태판단 산학연구 (Determination of driver stress industry-university project) Hyundai Mobis, Korea (Dec. 2019 ~ Jun. 2020)
- ISO 21062-2:2018 프로토콜에 따른 바이오넷 혈압계 모듈 BN1 의 임상 평가 (Clinical evaluation of Bionet sphygmomanometer module BN1 according to ISO 21062-2:2018 protocol)

주식회사 바이오넷 , Korea (May. 2020 ~ Nov. 2020)

- Development of real-time hemodynamic monitoring technology and prognostic indicators to improve cerebral perfusion during CPR
 National Research Foundation of Korea, Korea (Jun. 2020 ~ Feb. 2022)
- Development of Al Technology for Sleep Health Management based on Temporal Rhythm Analysis of Daily-life Brain-bio Signal Ministry of Science, ICT, Korea (Apr. 2021 ~ Dec. 2021)